<article article-type="research-article">
  <front>
    <article-meta>
      <title-group>
        <article-title>Extraction of Saturation Current and Ideality Factor from Measuring V oc and I sc of Photovoltaic Modules</article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group content-type="author">
        <contrib contrib-type="person">
          <name>
            <surname>Meyer</surname>
            <given-names>E L</given-names>
          </name>
          <email>emeyer@ufh.ac.za</email>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff0"/>
        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <aff id="aff0">
        <institution content-type="orgname">University of Fort Hare</institution>
        <institution content-type="orgdiv1">Institute of Technology</institution>
        <city>Alice</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </aff>
      <abstract>
				<p>Saturation current (I 0) and ideality factor (n) of a p-n junction solar cell are an indication of the quality of the cell. These two parameters are usually estimated from dark current-voltage measurements. In this study, a quick and easy method to determine these two parameters by measuring open-circuit, V oc , and short-circuit current, I sc , is presented. Solar cell designers can use this method as a grading or diagnostic tool to evaluate degradation in photovoltaic (PV) modules. In order to verify the V oc-I sc method, a series of experiments have been conducted on a single cell and a 36-cell module. Good agreement between our V oc-I sc method and dark I-V measurements was obtained. An application of the method on the performance degradation of a single-junction a-Si:H module revealed that the module's I 0 increased by more than three orders of magnitude and n increased by 65% after an outdoor exposure of 130 kWh/m 2. This increase in n indicates that after exposure, the recombination current in the cells' space charge region increased due to the light-induced formation of metastable defects. The method is also used to assess the quality of five PV module technologies and proved to be reliable despite defective cells in a module.</p>
			</abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
  <body/>
  <back/>
</article>
